(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T21:19:16.079206",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
半端ならK.O.
Half-hearted gets a K.O.!
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
So be it if you wanna fluff it up!
開演準備しちゃおうか
Let's get ready for the show!
泣いてても笑ってても愛してね
Cry, laugh, just love me, okay?
ほら say no
Come on, say no!
低音響かせろ
Let the bass resonate!
今宵は暗転パーティー
Tonight is a blackout party!
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Dance, dance, loneliness is sterilized, full house thank you!
痛みまで おシェアで
Share even the pain!
ここらでバイバイ let go
Saying bye-bye here, let go!
どんな劣等感だてて
No matter how inferior you feel,
即興の血小板で
with improvised platelets,
抑え込んで 突っ込んで 仕舞い込んじゃうでしょ
hold it in, thrust in, and dance away!
up and down なテンション
Up and down tension,
寝ぼえまいっちぇくってんの相当
napping right through is quite equivalent.
ドバッと噴き出すのは 本音の独り言
What bursts out is a solo of truth.
「別に興味ない」
"Not really interested."
「特に関係ない」
"It doesn't really matter."
塞ぎ込んで 舌尖絶頂へ
Pack it in to the tip of your tongue,
合図を奏でて prr-prr-prr-prr
play the signal prr-prr-prr-prr!
ほら集まって夜行だ
Come on, gather up, it's a night walk!
鳴いていこう
Keep on roaring!
半端ならK.O.
Half-hearted gets a K.O.!
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Dance, dance, loneliness is sterilized, full house thank you!
痛みまで おシェアで
Share even the pain!
今宵も暗転パーティーだ
Tonight is also a blackout party!
ああ もううぜっってえんだって現状に絶望
Ah, it's so annoying, I feel hopeless,
溜め込んだ痛みココロで絶叫
screaming with the pain stored in my heart.
誰も知らない ドブネズミの歌
The gutter rat's song that nobody knows,
騒いで聞かせましょう
let's make some noise and let them hear!
okay now, listen up, it's time for something new
it's gon get crazy wild, so hold on to this tune
いい でしょうか？ 今宵 は 僕 の show time
Is that alright? Tonight is my showtime.
同調 圧力 に 屈し た 皆さん eyo
To everyone who succumbed to peer pressure, eyo!
they want a revolution?
ha！ we 'll give it to ' em！
Ha! We'll give it to 'em!
take a stand now
my wish is your command！
my wish is your command!
you want a party?
follow behind me
カオス へ と ご 招待
An invitation to chaos,
窮鼠 は 猫 噛む 気 を つけ な
the cornered rat bites the cat, watch out.
rogue rat runaway
gotta get out of this place せーの 出 ない や
gotta get out of this place with no time to hesitate.
rogue rat run away 昼夜 逆転 反転 世界 (ratatata)
Rogue rat run away, day and night reversed world (ratatata).
rogue rat run away i won't stay in my own lane
つまらない や
it's so boring.
rogue rat run away 翻弄 し ちまう ぞ 追い付いて 風 の よう に 疼く よう に
Rogue rat run away, I'll toy with you, catch up like the wind, aching like a haze,
we 'll vanish into the night
we'll vanish into the night.
誰も 見 ちぁ い ない (no)
No one is looking (no),
今 に 見 て なさい (yo)
watch it now (yo).
僕 は 世間 の 奴 の 「 鼻 つまみ 者 」
I'm the "public nuisance" despised by the world.
squeak！ squeak！ they run away
Squeak! Squeak! They run away,
squeak！ squeak！ so far away
Squeak! Squeak! So far away.
ちゅーちゅーちゅーちゅーちゅーちゅーちゅー
Choo choo choo choo choo choo choo,
暴れまくれ
go wild!
they say i 'm scum, a loser
They say I'm scum, a loser,
too bad, i 've heard it all before
too bad, I've heard it all before.
my music 's all i need
My music's all I need,
tell my truth through melodies
wordplay that makes your heart boom！
Wordplay that makes your heart boom!
start up the party
we gon ' get rowdy
we gon' get rowdy.
ノイズ が 邪魔 を し て も
Even if the noise gets in the way,
隙 は 見せる な 食わ れ ちまう ぞ
don't show any gaps, you'll be eaten.
rogue rat run away
i will keep you on your feet 油断 し ない で
I will keep you on your feet, don't let your guard down.
rogue rat runaway
always keep you guessing 惑わせ
always keep you guessing, confounding you.
知らず知らず 秩序 乱す
Unknowingly disrupting the order,
we 'll vanish into the night
we'll vanish into the night.
hey ladies & gentlemen ya ya ya ya
let 's turn these streets into a rave
let's turn these streets into a rave.
自由 は どこ な の 僕 に 価値 は ある の
Where is my freedom? Do I have value?
現実 を 壊せ ば そこ は シャングリラ
If you break reality, it's Shangri-La.
rogue rat run away
gotta get out of this place せーの 出 ない や
gotta get out of this place with no time to hesitate.
rogue rat run away
昼夜 逆転 反転 世界 (ratatata)
day and night reversed world (ratatata).
rogue rat run away
i won't stay in my own lane つまらない や
I won't stay in my own lane, it's so boring.
rogue rat run away 翻弄 し ちまう ぞ 追い付いて 風 の よう に 疼く よう に
Rogue rat run away, I'll toy with you, catch up like the wind, aching like a haze,
we 'll vanish into the night
we'll vanish into the night.
yea yea yea yea yea yea！
Yea, yea, yea, yea, yea, yea!
誰も知らない ドブネズミの歌
The gutter rat's song that nobody knows,
騒いで聞かせましょう
let's make some noise and let them hear!
こっそり咲き乱れよ
Bloom in secret and riot!
痛みまで押し合って
Pushing against each other through the pain,
今宵もまた突っ走れ
let's dash forward tonight once again!
生まれて残す爪痕だけど
The scars we leave behind as we're born... even so,
ふふふ
fufuha...
世界中どこでも元気で
be well anywhere in the world,
ココロでバイバイLet go
saying goodbye from the heart, let go!
こっちまで元気でココロでバイバイLet go
Be well over here too, saying goodbye from the heart, let go!
バイバイ！ あたし 激 的 に Cute！
Bye-bye! I am dramatically cute!
What's up!
I am Chaos! The end of end!
A silver rat trapped in a cage of ice!
Your best friend Baelz takes us from hololive!
English! Whatever comes up!
終わりの果て　ザ・エンド！ 氷の檻に踏みにされし黒金の薔薇　何時の日ともハロウィンの　ハクスペルスです！
The end of the end, The End! The black-gold rose trampled in a cage of ice, Halloween's Hakos Baelz is here!
Witness me! Guys, it's finally, finally, finally my birthday!
It's finally, do you understand? It's been it's finally my birthday!
Welcome to my Birthday Live 2024, Dream Catcher!
I'm so thankful that I could do a birthday live for my real birthday this year, and I have a special, special stage name for which I'll talk about in a second.
But please, use the hashtag #BaeDay2024 to share your comments and your thoughts and screenshots and anything, because I'm gonna be reading it after the stream.
Thank you so much! I'm so excited! Look at this stage! I had an original stage designed. Oh my god! We've got the butterfly, we've got the water and fire.
How does that work? Nobody knows. It's so cheeny, I love it.
Thank you so much um for helping me design this stage. It's so cool. I'm my I'm so excited. I can't I can't get anything out.
But we have a lot of guests performing today, and we have a lot of songs, so you might not see MC Bae as much. It's gonna be song after song after song after song.
So, get ready! You're not ready! But also, stay until the very end because I have a very important announcement.
Yeah, not a little announcement, a big important announcement that you will never guess. はい！配信は最後まで見てて行けたら嬉しいなと思ってます。発表がありますので。はい。普通の発表じゃなくて超デカイ発表がありますの。なので最後までお楽しみに！
Yeah, not a little announcement, a big important announcement that you will never guess. So please stay tuned until the very end! I have a big announcement to share, not just a normal one, but a huge one, so please look forward to it!
The next song, and um, I hope you all enjoy it.
最初の曲ちょっと準備に ちょっとちょっと重いますので あの楽しみにして
I'm preparing a bit for the first song, so please look forward to it!
じゃあ、あとでね。オッケー オッケー バイバイ バイバイ バイバイ 行ってきます。バイバイ。
See you later, okay? Bye-bye! I'm off, bye-bye!
無限に生きたい 無限に生きられたら
I want to live forever, and if I could live forever,
全て叶う
everything would come true,
でもいろんなものがわたしを追い詰めていく
but various things drive me into a corner.
生きる残り時間 夢の座標 行方
The time I have left to live, the coordinates of my dream,
全部大事なものなのに
even though they're all important things.
いいさ ここらでちょっと 甘いもの食べていこう
All right, let's stay here for a little and eat something sweet.
そういう思考停止ばかり得意になった
When I just stopped thinking like that, I became proud.
歩いてきた道振り返ると イヤなことばかりでもううんざりだよ
When I look back on the road I walked down,
I get fed up with how it's nothing but things I didn't want.
触れるものを輝かせていく そんな道を生きてきたんだよ
Letting the things I touch shine,
that kind of path is the kind I wanted to live.
無性に生きたい 焦ってばかりの日々 全て消えそう
I desperately want to live.
All of the days that rushed by look like they'll disappear,
でもさぼってもみる だって疲れちゃうじゃない そんな矛盾思考
but I also slack off, because I get tired, right?
With such contradictory thoughts.
あたし頭どっか知らないうち打ったみたいだ
It's like my head was hit somewhere when I wasn't aware.
ずっと起き上がれる薬は置いていませんか？
Could you leave me some medicine
that'll keep me awake forever?
ぼそっと突っ立ってるだけでもう化石になってしまいそうなんだよ
Just by standing up quickly,
I feel like I'm going to turn into a fossil.
誰からも忘れられたような くすんだ存在になってしまおうよ
As though it was forgotten by everyone,
my existence is darkening.
いいさ ここらでちょっと根性を見せてやる
All right, let's stay here for a little,
and I'll show you my spirit.
自分でもた叩いて存在の証明
Slap yourself on the cheeks as proof that you exist.
歩いてきた道振り返らない イヤなことばかりでも前へ進め
I won't look back at the road I walked down.
It's all things I didn't want, but move on forward.
触れるものを輝かせていく そんな存在になって
Letting the things I touch shine,
I'll show you that!
見せるよ 見せるよ 見せるよ 見せるよ
I'll show you! I'll show you!
さあ 眠眠打破 昼夜逆転
So wake up, come on! Up until dawn
VOX AC30W
VOX AC30 watt amp
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが
バンド仲間でやっほー
The boy with the telecaster on his back
talks to his friends, says yahoo
アルバイトはネクラモード
That job that leaves you harrowed
対バンドにはATフィールド
At-field - you can't pass through
人見知り宣言で逃げる気か boy
You want to scream I am shy and run far away, boy?
ゆーてれ お坊ちゃんお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も
Listen, little kid, younger girl, know that money and talent
なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
What a nuisance, means nothing, makes me feel calloused
boys be ambitious... like this old man
Boys be ambitious... like this older man
likes all the men, 長い前髪 君誰の信者
likes all the men, who are you devoted to?
勘違いすんな 教祖はオマエだ
You're the host of this mad show, don't forget and play naive
信者... 信者...
Devoted... devoted...
ロキロキのロックンロックンローリング
鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
Roki roki ro roki roku ro
Strums of my electric guitar you perceive
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ 君の全てを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come now, don't fear, be daring
Let it out, don't fear the staring
ロキロキのロックンロックンローリング
さあ 日進月歩 いい曲書いてる？ 動員増えてる？
Roki roki ro roki roku ro
Making progress, building a good song?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね。」
You have an image to the public but you're not really famous so things are rough for you
はっきり言うなよ匿名アイコン
Don't say lies to me, drawn icon
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
Don't show lies to me, live icon
いい気絶こいて自意識まだ boy
Grow up and forget all of your self-consciousness, boy
ぶっちょけどんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
Listen now, no matter how clever or the tricks up your sleeve,
that facade in 10 years will no longer deceive
ぶっちゃけどんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
No matter how clever or the tricks up your sleeve,
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
that facade in 10 years will no longer deceive
boys be ambitious... like this old man
Boys be ambitious... like this older man
生き抜くためだ 決めろ take a selfie
Stay alive and present, play the game and take a selfie
selfie, selfie...
ロキロキのロックンロックンローリング
スペランカー人生でもいいと
Roki roki ro roki roku ro
Doesn't matter if it's a sappy love song
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ目の前のあの子を 撃ち抜いてみせろよ
C'mon, now be bold. That girl -
Be confident, give her a twirl
ロキロキのロックンロックンローling
Roki roki ro roku rok n ro
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
You know, I won't be happy if we play half-hearted
スタジオに運ばれたスロートコードは 安心 不安 プレッシャーでいっぱい
The cough medicine we brought with us is more than expected,
filled with pressure, relief, apprehension
「実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません」
Don't blame me, I can't sing since I had a bad cold yesterday!
は！？は！？は！？は！？
Huh? Huh? What!? Huh!
はぁ…寝言は寝て言え、ベイビー！
Cut it out you're being such a...
baby, baby...
死んじまうぜねぇぞ お互いにさ！
We aren't gonna die, oh no you'll never see us dead!
ロキロキのロックンロックンローリング
鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
Roki roki no roku roku ro
Strums of my electric guitar you perceive
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ君の全てを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come now, don't fear, be daring
Let it out, don't fear the staring
ロキロキのロックンロックンローリング
セレクティブに関係した aw don't stop, don't stop
Roki roki ro roku roku ro
さあ君の全てを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come now, don't fear, be daring
Let it out, don't fear the staring
ロキロキのロックンロックンローリング
Roki roki ro roku roku ro
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ 死ぬんじゃねぇぞ
You aren't gonna find us dead
死にたかんねぇの お互い様だ！
Both of us don't want to die,
you'll never find us gone!
死んじまうぜねぇぞ お互いにさ！
We aren't gonna die, oh no you'll never see us dead!
キミと 一緒がいちばん
With you, together is best,
好きよってもっとぎゅっとね
hold me even tighter if you love me!
キミを 新しい場所へと
To a new place with you,
引っぱってっちゃお る・らんら!
I'll drag you along, ru-ran-ra!
遅れないでね
Don't fall behind, okay?
飛んでけすごいな 誰が?
Flying away, how amazing. Who?
私たちですよ!
It's us!
線引はないの いやっほ 楽しい宴
No boundaries, yippee, a fun feast!
ぜったい終わらない魔法かけて
Cast a magic spell that never ends
ドキドキの前夜祭
A heart-pounding eve festival
遊んで遊んでばかりがいいな
Playing and playing is all I want
でしょ? やっぱりやっぱりそうでしょう?
Right? Of course it is!
お祭りよいしょで仲良し
Cozying up at the festival, getting along
君へのよいしょは自然体
Being natural when cozying up to you
お出かけの順序は スイッチ入ってハイになって完了だ!
Getting ready is complete when we flip the switch and get high!
甘いデリカシーで
With sweet delicacy,
ほんのりさりげあっさりぴったり恋しちゃう
softly, casually, simply, and perfectly falling in love!
キミと 一緒がいちばん
With you, together is best,
好きよってもっとぎゅっとね
hold me even tighter if you love me!
キミを 新しい場所へと
To a new place with you,
引っぱってっちゃお る・らんら!
I'll drag you along, ru-ran-ra!
ホント 一緒にいたいな
Really, I want to be together,
邪魔されたくないんだもん
because I don't want to be disturbed!
キミに 秘密の場所では
In our secret place with you,
張りきっちゃうよ る・らんら る?らんら! だよ
I'll do my best, ru-ran-ra, ru-ran-ra!
ポイ捨てしないで 誰の? 君たちの拍手!
Don't throw it away. Whose? Your applause!
大切なお合図 いやっふ 楽しい集い
A precious signal, yippee, a joyful gathering.
断然おもしろい筈だから
Because it's definitely going to be fun,
ズキズキの感謝祭
a throbbing thanksgiving festival!
翻って翻ってみせてよほらね
Turn around and show me, see?
すごい? やっぱりやっぱり、ね! すごい!
Amazing? Of course, right? Amazing!
過激なワッショイでみらふる
With extreme festivities, a miracle
私もワッショイで保健体育
and me celebrating with health and P.E.
お休みのコールは スリーとツーとワンでもっと完了だ!
The rest call is complete with three, two, and one!
ゆるいテレパシーが
With loose telepathy,
やんわりそっくりおっとりぷっくり恋なのかな
gently, just like that, softly and plumply, is this love?
あのね 応援させてよ
Hey, let me cheer you on,
いつだってやっぱ元気に
because I always want you to be energetic!
あのおさ 踊りたいこのとき
Hey, when I want to dance like this,
おいってっちゃってじだんだ ふむ?
stomping my feet as I go, hmm?
本気 応援したいな
I really want to cheer you on,
落ち込みたくないんだもん
because I don't want to feel down!
あのね 冒険夢見て
Hey, dreaming of adventures,
知らないフリ
pretending not to know,
じだんだじだんだだね
stomping, stomping away!
キミと 一緒がいちばん
With you, together is best,
好きよってもっとぎゅっとね
hold me even tighter if you love me!
キミを 新しい場所へと
To a new place with you,
引っぱってっちゃお る・らんら!
I'll drag you along, ru-ran-ra!
ホント 一緒にいたいな
Really, I want to be together,
邪魔されたくないんだもん
because I don't want to be disturbed!
キミに 秘密の場所では
In our secret place with you,
張りきっちゃうよ る・らんら る?らんら! だよ
I'll do my best, ru-ran-ra, ru-ran-ra!
ほいってしないで 誰の?
Don't throw it away. Whose?
君たちの拍手!
Your applause!
大切な合図 いやっふ 嬉しい集い
A precious signal, yippee, a joyful gathering.
断然おもしろい筈だから
Because it's definitely going to be fun,
ずきずきの患者さん
a throbbing patient!
回して回して見せてよほらね
Turn it around and show me, see?
すごい? やっぱりやっぱり、ね! すごい!
Amazing? Of course, right? Amazing!
過激なワッショイでパワフル
With extreme festivities, powerful
私もワッショイでほけんしつ
and me celebrating with the nurse's office.
お休みのコールは スリーとツーとワンでもっと完了だ!
The rest call is complete with three, two, and one!
ゆるいテレパシーが
With loose telepathy,
やんわりそっくりおっとりぷっくり恋なのかな
gently, just like that, softly and plumply, is this love?
あのね 応援させてよ
Hey, let me cheer you on,
いつだってやっぱ元気に
because I always want you to be energetic!
あのさ 踊りたいこのとき
Hey, when I want to dance like this,
置いてっちゃってじだんだ ふむ?
leaving it behind, stomping my feet, hmm?
本気 応援したいな
I really want to cheer you on,
落ち込みたくないんだもん
because I don't want to feel down!
あのね 冒険夢見て
Hey, dreaming of adventures,
知らないフリ
pretending not to know,
じだんだじだんだだね
stomping, stomping away!
キミと 一緒がいちばん
With you, together is best,
好きよってもっとぎゅっとね
hold me even tighter if you love me!
キミを 新しい場所へと
To a new place with you,
引っぱってっちゃお る・らんら!
I'll drag you along, ru-ran-ra!
ホント 一緒にいたいな
Really, I want to be together,
邪魔されたくないんだもん
because I don't want to be disturbed!
キミに 秘密の場所では
In our secret place with you,
張りきっちゃうよ る・らんら る?らんら! だよ
I'll do my best, ru-ran-ra, ru-ran-ra!
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
This single ray of light illuminating the chaotic internet of the Reiwa era
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing a smile to the geeks drifting in the electronic sea
未来の平和をお約束
Promising peace for the future
躁鬱だけどまかせとけ
Manic-depressive, but leave it to me
インターネット・エンジェル ただいま降臨
Internet Angel has arrived right now!
社会をやめろ 家族をやめろ 人間関係をやめろ
Quit society, quit family, quit human relationships!
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
Right now, bathe in the pale light in a dim room!
大丈夫 こわかったこと全部上書きするからね
It's okay, I'll overwrite everything that scared you
現実よりも crazy for you
Even more than reality, crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
The information-overloaded internet that's driving us crazy
今すぐ救出してあげるよ ダーリン ダーリン
I'll rescue you right now, darling, darling
ウソはウソであると見抜けるし この愛は暴走しちゃうし
I can tell lies are lies, and this love runs out of control
壊れてしまうけど
Even though it will break
考えなくていいんだよ もうすぐ楽になるからね
You don't need to think, you'll feel better soon
脳内にゃんにゃんしゃする poison radio
Poison radio doing nyan-nyan in your brain
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
This is a supernova rising upon the chaotic modern cyberspace
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing happiness to all geeks of the internet
未来の平和をお約束
I shall promise you eternal peace
インターネット・エンジェルただいま降臨
Internet angel, presenting to you right now!
社会をやめろ 家族をやめろ
Society? Nonexist! Family? Nonexist!
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
I'ma get back to my corner and bathe under the room light
大丈夫怖かったこと全部上書きするからね
Don't be afraid. I'll wipe out all fear and depression
現実よりも crazy for you
More than in reality, crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
Overwhelming, mind-blowing social network
今救い出してあげるよ ダーリン ダーリン
I'm gonna get you outta there now, darling, darling
ウソはウソだと見抜けるし この愛は暴走しちゃうし
Truths and lies, love and hate, all push me out of control
壊れてしまうけど
I'm at the brink of insanity
考えなくていいんだよ
Now if you're searching for the very way out
もうすぐ楽になるからね
I'm always around to set your mind free
脳内に鳴りやむしゃする poison radio
The poison radio keeps flowing in me
麻薬より甘いよ
Even sweeter than my addiction
いいね良くないね キミにとっては毒だね
Like it, dislike it, maybe this is poisonous for you
いいね良くないね それでも飲むんだね
Like it, dislike it, but you're gonna drink it anyway
いいね良くないね 二人のヒミツだね
Like it, dislike it, let's keep it a secret, always
わたしだけ見ててね
Devote your attention to me
まるで天使のように微笑む 強めの幻覚 internet girl
Just like an angel, I bring smile and healing
そして悪魔みたいにささやく アナタだけの needy girl
And like a demon, I whisper my feeling
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバードーズ
Insufficient sleep and infinite desire for approval
ノウテン直撃する私たちだけの宗教と光
Implanting into our minds our glory and religion
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら侵食する恋
Our romance is universe-blowing and beyond all ration
何度も贈られる毒電波を優しさだけで包んで
Toxic radio wrapped in sweetness, sending to you again and again
逆さまのコンピュータと断片的なカウンセリング
Psychedelic consultation on a flipped-over computer
煌めく屋上で穏やかな夢見心地の旋律
On the sparkling rooftop rings the dreamy melody
夕暮れ時にさよならの練習をして
Rehearsing goodbye by the twilight
壊して愛して許して狂って
Break it, love it, forgive it, get mad
狂って狂って甘く狂わせて
Get mad, get mad, get mad in illusion...
ゆらぎ始める世界 曖昧になる風景
And so the world starts to disintegrate
あなただけが映っているメモリー
All visions suddenly fade away
神様なんていないよ このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
What remains from the chaos is nothing but your memory
SNSというビン詰め地獄に救済を
There's simply no such thing as miracle
過去の歴史は見ないふり あなたのためならすぐそばに
All these enjoyments in the internet are but a colorful masquerade
インターネットエンジエル 可愛く参上
To this bottled hell of social network, I shall bring salvation
まるで天使のように抱きつく 強めの幻覚 internet girl
What has passed is not to be seen
そして悪魔みたいにキスする アナタだけの 3D girl
I'll be by your side whenever you need
狂わせて狂わせて狂わせて狂わせて 甘く狂わせて
Just like an angel, I'm holding you in embrace
壊しちゃ愛して許して狂って狂って狂って狂って 甘く狂わせて
Drown in illusion, call me internet girl
ゆらぎ始める世界 曖昧になる風景
And like a demon, imprint kiss on your face
あなただけが映っているメモリー
Belonging only to you. A 3D girl
神様なんていないよ
Gods don't even exist
このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
This absurd internet is a colorful psychedelic
SNSというビン詰め地獄に救済を
To this bottled hell of social network, I shall bring salvation
過去の歴史は見ないふり あなたのためならすぐそばに
What has passed is not to be seen
インターネットエンジェル 可愛く参上
I'll be by your side whenever you need
まるで天使のように突き刺く 強めの幻覚 internet girl
Internet angel, hereby debut!
そして悪魔みたいにキスする アナタだけの 3D girl
Just like an angel, I'm holding you in embrace
インターネット・エンジェル
Internet angel...
Let's go!
Kissで目覚めて CHA・CHAのリズムで
I awaken with a kiss, with the rhythm of a chacha
甘く モザイクMidnight
A sweet, mosaic midnight
わざと焦らして 意外に無邪気に
You tease me on purpose, unexpectedly innocent
遥か 異国のMoonlight
The moonlight of a distant foreign country
夢で見た景色と
The scenery i saw in my dreams
幾つかの運命(さだめ)と めまぐるしく 変わり始めた
And the many destinies began to change dizzyingly
光と影の誘惑
A seduction of light and shadow
熱くVenus 燃えてVenus 君の瞳(め)が 胸を焦がす
Hot Venus, burning Venus, your eyes scorch my heart
シルクロード 愛は千里 ためらう なら 忘れ たい
The silk road, this far away love, if you're going to hesitate, I want to forget
熱くVenus 感じ てVenus 嵐の様 に 風を見せて
Hot Venus, feel it, Venus, show me the wind like a storm
君が答え 知っ ている 愛の輝き 放て
You know the answer, shooting sparks of love
赤い唇が DANGER
Red lips are DANGER
飲み干して むき出した ナイフ突き刺さる
Drink it down, a bared knife pierces through
恋愛の形式 奇跡ならない式
Romance's format, a ceremony that doesn't become a miracle
遥か異国のランデブー
A rendez-vous in a distant foreign country
真珠のきらめきで 愛に引きずられて
Dragged into love by the shimmer of pearls
琥珀色の 息切れに消えた
Faded into amber-colored breathlessness
白昼夢をも見出したい
I want to discover even a daydream
砂漠さえも満たしたい
I want to fill even the desert
熱くビーナス 燃えてビーナス
Hot Venus, burning Venus
星のデルタ 夜空を染め
Delta of stars, dyeing the night sky
散々クロス 揺れる大地
Scattered crosses, the shaking earth
指先で見つめたい
I want to gaze at it with my fingertips
熱くビーナス 感じてビーナス
Hot Venus, feeling Venus
稲妻より 光見せて
Show me a light brighter than lightning
新世界を操る空に
In the sky controlling the new world
愛の輝き 放て
Release the brilliance of love
先輩たち 私を試すな
Seniors, don't test me
急かすな 無理無理無理 この俺が劣ったことないっす
Don't rush me, no way, this guy has never been inferior
最高の時間にしよぜ
Let's make it the best time ever
熱くビーナス 燃えてビーナス
Hot Venus, burning Venus
君の目が 胸を焦す
Your eyes scorch my chest
シルクロード 愛は千里
Silk Road, love is a thousand miles
ためらうなら 忘れたい
If you're hesitating, I want to forget
熱くビーナス 燃えてビーナス
Hot Venus, burning Venus
星のデルタ 夜空を染め
Delta of stars, dyeing the night sky
散々クロス 揺れる大地
Scattered crosses, the shaking earth
指先で見つめたい
I want to gaze at it with my fingertips
熱くビーナス 感じてビーナス
Hot Venus, feeling Venus
稲妻より 光見せて
Show me a light brighter than lightning
新世界を操る空に
In the sky controlling the new world
愛の輝き 放て
Release the brilliance of love
熱くビーナス 燃えてビーナス
Hot Venus, burning Venus
星のデルタ 夜空を染め
Delta of stars, dyeing the night sky
散々クロス 揺れる大地
Scattered crosses, the shaking earth
砕けた心が濾過できなくて
Unable to filter my shattered heart,
涙はそっと枯れていく
my tears quietly dried up.
もう一粒も流れなくて
Unable to shed even one more drop,
可笑しいねって笑ってる
I laugh, saying 'how funny'.
酷烈な人生 あなたを遮る迷路の荊棘
A cruel life, maze-like brambles obstructing you,
濁世の闇 立ちふさがる
the darkness of this corrupt world standing in your way.
君は誰よりも憂う人
You're someone who sorrows more than anyone.
だから今僕らは溺れかけている寸前だろう
So right now we're probably on the verge of drowning.
正しい呼吸に救われた 今はいつか死ぬために生きているだけだ
Saved by correct breathing, now I'm just living in order to die someday.
雨が嫌いな理由を知る とき深いところで思い出すこと
Knowing why I hate the rain, remembering deep inside,
そう 大粒のシャボン玉なら きっとふかふかでしとしと
yes, if it's large soap bubbles, surely fluffy and gentle.
地面の色を見て歩く 水たまりのない場所 選んでる
Walking while looking at the ground color, choosing places without puddles.
さっては 不遇な道を逸れるため 自己防衛だってするんでしょう
Well, you do self-defense to stray from unfortunate paths, don't you?
僕は今 人間です 今日も明日も その次の日も
I am human right now, today, tomorrow, and the day after that.
認めるのは そのくらいでいい みんな別の息を食べてる
Admitting that much is fine, everyone breathes different air.
そう 君も今 人間です その姿が嫌いなだけで
Yes, you are human too right now, just hating that appearance.
壊れた心が濾過できなくて
Unable to filter my broken heart,
涙はそっと枯れていく
my tears quietly dry up.
もう一粒も流れなくて
Unable to shed even another drop,
可笑しいねって笑ってる
I laugh, saying, "How funny is that?"
酷烈な人生
A cruel life,
あなたを遮る迷路の荊棘
maze-like thorns obstructing you.
ひとひらの花が散るために
For a single petal to fall,
水も土も光もその種も
water, earth, light, and its very seed—
僕の目の前にあるものが
everything right before my eyes,
その意味も過去も未来も
its meaning, past, and future—
ひとつ欠けると生まれないぜ
if even one is missing, nothing is born.
僕も君もあの人も
Neither me, nor you, nor anyone else.
なんでもないと言いながら過去の荷物を君に背負わせる
While saying it's nothing, I make you carry the baggage of the past.
運命が通せんぼする 勘違い 自業自得だよ
Destiny blocking your way? It's a misunderstanding, you reap what you sow.
でも状況が良くないからね
But because the situation isn't good,
逃げたいよね 生きたいよね
you want to run away, you want to live.
この体を投げ出すその瞬間があるとするば
If there is a moment when you throw this body away,
この世の闇切り裂いてさ ここに生まれた意味を探そうか
let's cleave through the world's darkness and search for the meaning of our birth here.
終わりの始まり 始まれば最後だ 人生だから
The beginning of the end—once it starts, it's the final life, because this is life.
途方もない旅の終わりに 今しかない時があるのだろう
At the end of an endless journey, there must be a moment that exists only now.
雨に溺れることはないな
There's no drowning in the rain,
それでもなんだか息苦しいな
yet somehow it's hard to breathe.
いつか死ぬために生きてるなんて
Living just to die someday—
それならさ それならば
if that's so, if that's the case,
もう壊れない 壊れない 壊れない 心の鈴を鳴らそう
let's ring the bell of our hearts, never breaking again.
曇天だろう 泥まみれさ
Even if it's overcast, even if we're covered in mud,
どこもかしこも 今この世のゆくえを塞げる迷路に線を引こうぜ
let's draw a line everywhere through the maze blocking the world's path.
その線がさ 重なる地図 君を照らすために咲く花さ
That line is an overlapping map—a flower blooming to illuminate you.
Baelz, you're on in five.
Never did she think she would be living out her wildest dreams.
Ayy, come on, check-in time
look what I got tonight
上モノが届いたな
Top-shelf goods have arrived,
ウサビに違和感 quite the dangerous stuff
quite the dangerous stuff with a strange vibe.
その末端価格 教らんないやつの
The street price is something you wouldn't know.
Greetings, buddy, hit that beat!
One verse ゆるい flo 横目に 踏み固める rhymer
One verse, ignoring the loose flow, a rhymer pounding it down.
活殺 活かす 殺す は こちら次第だ 無頼漢
Whether to revive or kill is up to us, you outlaws.
Deal has just begun now
一騒ぎ 起こそうぜ brother
let's cause a ruckus, brother.
正気の沙汰じゃ い ら ない ね badass bae
Acting sane isn't needed here, badass bae.
In this bad bad biz
カラダ を 張れよ
put your body on the line,
put your body on the line.
助手席に 座れよ
Sit in the passenger seat,
心拍数が 上げ 止まらない
heart rate soaring and never stopping,
火 を つけた ように
like setting a fire.
Baby, feeling lucky?
ここ のっぴん が 最後 狂気 なら プライド
If the end is madness, pride is all we have.
All in, all in, no backing out risk your life on this
and watch it go boom!
ehh…
Ehh...
aight come on check-in time
look what i got tonight
上モノが届いたな
Fresh goods have arrived,
ウワサに違いん quaint the dangerous stuff
a rumor-defying, quite the dangerous stuff.
その末端価格教えらんないやつ
Can't tell you the street value of that.
greetings, buddy, hit that beat！
Greetings, buddy, hit that beat!
one verse ゆるい flo 横目に踏み固める rhymer
One verse, loose flo, stepping firm past it, rhymer.
活殺、活かす 殺す は こちら次第だ 無頼漢
Give life or take it, it's up to us, outlaws.
deal has just begun now
人騒ぎ起こそうぜ brother
Let's start a ruckus, brother.
正気の沙汰 じゃないね badass bae
Not in your right mind, badass Bae.
in this bad bad biz
カラダを 張れよ
stretch your body out,
stretch your body out.
助手席に 座れよ
Sit in the passenger seat,
心拍数が 上げ止まらない
heart rate won't stop rising,
火を つけた ように
like setting a fire.
baby, feeling lucky？
Baby, feeling lucky?
ここ 乗っぴん が最後 狂気 なら プライド
This ride is the last, if it's madness, it's pride.
all in, all in, no backing out
risk your life on this
and watch it go boom！
and watch it go boom!
we 'll make it go boom！, ah ah ah
We'll make it go boom!, ah, ah, ah.
ready for it？ watch it go boom！
Ready for it? Watch it go boom!
we 'll make it go boom！, eh eh eh
We'll make it go boom!, eh, eh, eh.
ready for it？ watch it go boom！
Ready for it? Watch it go boom!
sorry, don't care ' bout it 's my dirty mouth
Sorry, don't care 'bout it, it's my dirty mouth,
今更 クリーン じゃやりてけない
can't go clean now anyway.
回しっぱ pick all my shit up
Leaving it recording, pick all my shit up.
頭ん中 叩き込みな (choose the best)
Pound it into your head (choose the best).
drivin ' drivin ' スタイル フリー ではないが
Drivin' drivin', style ain't totally free,
pen and paper ＜ smaller mic and tequila
pen and paper < smaller mic and tequila.
直接フロア まで突っ込むのが早いな driver
Fast driver plunging straight to the floor.
即決 grade b
Instant decision, Grade B,
b for the bae
in this bad bad biz
カラダを 張れよ
stretch your body out,
stretch your body out.
助手席に 座れよ
Sit in the passenger seat,
心拍数が 上げ止まらない
heart rate won't stop rising,
火を つけた ように
like setting a fire.
baby, feeling lucky？
Baby, feeling lucky?
ここ 乗っぴん が最後 狂気 なら プライド
This ride is the last, if it's madness, it's pride.
all in, all in, no backing out
risk your life on this
and watch it go boom！
and watch it go boom!
we 'll make it go boom！, ah ah ah
We'll make it go boom!, ah, ah, ah.
ready for it？ watch it go boom！
Ready for it? Watch it go boom!
we 'll make it go boom！, eh eh eh
We'll make it go boom!, eh, eh, eh.
ready for it？ watch it go boom！
Ready for it? Watch it go boom!
you in？ you in？
You in? You in?
you only got one shot！
You only got one shot!
一見は これだから
Since it's a first glance like this,
「走れ！」
"Run!"
go run away
to find a better game
go on go run away
bet you want it, make it go boom！
bet you want it, make it go boom!
can you follow me このスピード 夜通し
Can you follow me at this speed all night long?
走れなきゃ 袋叩き
If you can't run, you're cornered.
腹 ここで 括れ what a day
Brace yourself right here, what a day.
抜け出せたなら
If you manage to escape,
know you wanna make it go boom！
know you wanna make it go boom!
okay now, listen up, it 's time for something new
Okay now, listen up, it's time for something new,
it 's gon ' get crazy wild, so hold on to this tune
it's gon' get crazy wild, so hold on to this tune.
いい でしょうか？ 今宵 は 僕 の showtime
Is that alright? Tonight is my showtime,
同調 圧力 に 屈し た 皆さん eyo
ayo to everyone who caved to peer pressure.
they want a revolution？
They want a revolution?
ha , we 'll give it to ' em
Ha, we'll give it to 'em.
take a stand now
my wish is your command
you want a party？
You want a party?
follow behind me
カオス へ と ご 招待
an invitation to chaos.
窮鼠 は 猫 噛む 気 を つけ な
The cornered mouse bites the cat, watch out.
rogue rat runaway
gotta get out of this place せわし ない や
gotta get out of this place, can't stay still.
rogue rat runaway
昼夜 逆転 反転 世界
day and night reversed, inverted world.
rogue rat runaway
i won ' t stay in my own lane つまらない や
I won't stay in my own lane, how boring.
rogue rat runaway
翻弄 し ちゃう 追いかけて
I'll toy with you, chase after me
風 の よう に
like the wind,
翳る よう に
like a fading haze.
we 'll vanish into the night
We'll vanish into the night.
誰も 見 ちゃ いない (no)
No one is looking (no),
今 に 見 て なさい (yo)
just watch me now (yo).
僕は 世間 の 奴 の 『 鼻 つまみ 者 』
I'm society's outcast nuisance.
squeak , squeak they run away
Squeak, squeak, they run away,
squeak , squeak so far away
squeak, squeak, so far away.
ちゅーちゅーちゅーちゅー 暴れまくれ
Choo-choo-choo-choo, go wild!
they say i 'm scum , a loser
They say I'm scum, a loser,
too bad , i 've heard it all before
too bad, I've heard it all before.
my music 's all i need
My music's all I need,
tell my truth through melodies
wordplay that makes your heart boom
start up the party
we gon ' get rowdy
we gon' get rowdy.
ノイズ が 邪魔 を し て も
Even if the noise gets in the way,
隙 は 見せる な 食わ れ ちゃう ぞ
don't show any openings, or you'll be eaten.
rogue rat runaway
i will keep you on your feet 油断 し ない で
I will keep you on your feet, don't let your guard down.
rogue rat runaway
always keep you guessing 惑わせ て
always keep you guessing, throw you off.
知らず知らず 秩序 乱す
Unknowingly disrupting order,
we 'll vanish into the night
we'll vanish into the night.
hey ladies and gentlemen , ha
Hey ladies and gentlemen, ha,
ya - ya - ya - ya
ya-ya-ya-ya,
let 's turn these streets into a rave
let's turn these streets into a rave.
自由 は どこ な の
Where is freedom?
僕 に 価値 は ある の
Do I have any value?
現実 を 壊せ ば そこ は シャングリラ
If you break reality, it's Shangri-La.
rogue rat runaway
gotta get out of this place せわし ない や
gotta get out of this place, can't stay still.
rogue rat runaway
昼夜 逆転 反転 世界
day and night reversed, inverted world.
rogue rat runaway
i won ' t stay in my own lane つまらない や
I won't stay in my own lane, how boring.
rogue rat runaway
翻弄 し ちゃう 追いかけて
I'll toy with you, chase after me
風 の よう に
like the wind,
翳る よう に
like a fading haze.
we 'll vanish into the night
We'll vanish into the night.
We'll vanish into the night
チューバーどこなの
Where is the VTuber?
ぼくにかちは あるのの 現実を 壊せば
Do I even have any worth? If you break reality,
そこはシャングリラ
that place is Shangri-La.
rogue rat runaway
We'll vanish into the night
あーーりあーーと！
Thank you so much!
Did you like it?
I told you there was not going to be any time for breaks.
It was going to be song after song after song!
I hope you enjoyed it,
and we had a lot of guest songs, and I'm so happy and honored that I was able to perform with so many members that I look up to
We had a lot of guest songs, and I'm so happy and honored that I was able to perform with so many members that I look up to
and that have helped me so much on my idol journey.
who have helped me so much on my idol journey.
I could cry!
But the last thing that you heard was something very special.
Did you know? I just came out with a new song.
What? That last song was a new song? What?
None other original song! Yes, that's right!
None other than an original song! Yes, that's right!
The last song I just sang called R×R×R is my new original, and the music video will be coming out after the stream, so please do check it out!
But, that's actually not the major announcement.
Did you think that was a major? No, the actual major announcement is what comes with the song!
Did you think that was the major one? No, the actual major announcement is what comes with the song!
Little Rat has been cooking, and I bring you my first album, ZODIAC!
My first album is finally out. It consists of 13 brand-new songs—13! Not one, not two, 13 brand-new songs!
ZODIAC by yours truly, Hakos Baelz. I've been working on this for so long, and it has cost me blood, sweat and tears,
but it's finally out. The digital version will be available at midnight at your local time. I'll be doing a first listen at midnight JST tonight,
so make sure you go and check out the stream. Maybe you can come listen to it with me.
But for those who like physical CD sets, yes, there is a physical CD that will be available for purchase after the stream as well.
And there's also a ZODIAC theme fan! There's a fan called An'yo! Kakkoikunai? It's so cool!
And there's also a ZODIAC theme fan! There's a fan called An'yo! Isn't it cool? It's so cool!
まいどいなるはこすべーるどの お誕生日おめでとー！
My dear Fräulein Hakos Baelz, I bid you a happy birthday.
新たな年齢を迎えることがきでんのさらなる成長と成功につながるよう、私も心から祈っている。
I pray that this milestone brings with it even greater growth and success for you.
きっと素晴らしい1年になるだろう。
This coming year will surely be a momentous one.
あー、もちろん日々の検問は怠らぬように。
Of course, I trust you will not shirk your regular studies.
ということで、はこすちゃんわっさー！はじめまして、声優の悠木碧です。
And with that, Hakos-chan, what's up? Nice to meet you, I'm voice actress Aoi Yuuki.
改めまして、この度は お誕生日 おめでとうございます！
And I would like to personally wish you a very happy birthday!
実は、え、はこすさんのことはですね、インターネットを通じて私も少し前から存じ上げておりました。
As a matter of fact, thanks to the power of the internet, I found out about you a little while ago.
なんでも、私もちょうねんふんでぐれちゃふで参加させていただいているアニメ、幼女戦記を大好きでいてくれているというね、噂を耳にしたときはとっても嬉しかったです。
I was so happy to hear that you were a big fan of the anime The Saga of Tanya the Evil, in which I play Tanya von Degurechaff.
ね、言葉の壁を乗り越えて、はこすさんの目と耳、そして心にもね、自分の携わる作品が届いて、愛していただけているなんて感激です。
I was moved by the fact that a work I participated in was able to cross the language barrier to reach your eyes, ears, and heart.
いつか一緒にね、ロスロスロスが歌えたらいいななんて思っちゃいました。
Maybe someday we can "Los! Los! Los!" together. Wouldn't that be nice?
これからも、可愛いカオスを世界に振りまく素敵なネズミさんでいてください。
I hope you'll keep spreading your cute chaos around the world as the wonderful rat we all know.
本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます！結木あおいでした！バイバイ！
Once again, happy birthday! This has been Yuki Aoi! Bye-bye!
I have no words.
I appreciate it.
Truly, thank you.
Um, I am the biggest Yuki-fan, and I just wanted to cry.
Tanya, I love you!
I will... I want... I'm missing words. I can't speak!
Thank you. Thank you so much for making this happen.
Thank you!
God, she knows me!
Okay, um... where... What do I do now? Where was I?
Oh, okay. I just had a... So, I have birthday merch!
Um, yeah. I have birthday merch. I'm kind of shook right now.
Um, you may be shook too by what you see, but hey, I have birthday merch and I'm coming out with...
the Dakimakura. I'm in shock.
But, baby, you'll be in shock, too, because I said I was never doing this, but hey, turns out this is a birthday that I've always dreamed of.
And hey, it's a birthday you've always dreamed of, cuz now you get a Dakimakura, which I said I was never gonna do.
But hey, it's pretty cute. You should get it. It's very realistic. This is what I look like when I wake up in the morning.
Ha, there you go.
Um, I also have a second good... What else did I make?
I don't know, my brain's...
Oh, I made Apple and Bae-nanas fridge magnets. They're pretty cute. You should get that, too.
You can put stuff on the fridge. They're pretty cute. You should get it.
Um, I think I had one more item. I had a phone strap.
Bae needs Bae needs oxygen right now.
And also a phone strap because it's good for travel. Yeah, it is very handy. You should get it.
Um, and also, I have a situation voice.
It is a very special message for my brats and for myself in four years' time.
Um, yeah, you should get it.
Um, also, normally there is limited goods, but, uh, there aren't any this year.
Because I decided, I'm going to sign every single person's postcard if you buy the full set.
You know, you only get a birthday once every four years.
And you know what? I think we all you all deserve it, you know? I don't care if my hand falls off.
If you buy the full set, you are guaranteed a signed postcard.
Hi, thank you so much for supporting me. Please get it.
There is no limited sale, only the limited period the entire merch is available, so you don't have to rush to get in line.
You can just get it within the normal sale period.
Yeah, um...
Thank you. Yoshiko Aisumasu.
Um, that is all for today. I'm going to go cry now.
Um, I hope that was good.
Bye, I've got to go. What just happened?
Oh, my God. I need water. Okay, bye.
Oh!
"Play with Fire" was the song I had.
Did you want an encore?
My heart is still shaking, but it's okay,
because we still have one more song until the end of the show.
And I wanted to finish off with a bang!
And I would like to perform one more song for you guys as the encore song, and it's a very important song to me, very special to my heart.
And I'd like to perform one more song for you guys as the encore. It's a very important song to me, very special to my heart.
So I hope you'll listen. Hey, goes up, Kakurenbo!
「いっせーのーで」で鳴り響いたスタートの合図
"One, two, three" the starting signal echoed out
なぞった線で結んだ世界 色付けていくここから
A world connected by traced lines, adding color from here on out
物心付く頃 既に此処にあった
By the time I was old enough to understand, it was already here
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は 夕日と共に蘇る
Someone else's memories that aren't mine come flooding back with the setting sunset
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して 落書きの中に 1つの答えを見つけた
Pulling out a worn-out picture book, amidst the scribbles I found one answer
自分の価値観を疑って どこまでだって堕ちていけるの
Doubting my own worth, wondering just how far down I can fall
生きてるだけ無駄だって 私の事なんて見捨ててよ
"It's useless just being alive," abandon me already
どうせ邪魔になって 迷惑ばかりかけてしまうからね
After all, I'll just get in the way and cause trouble for everyone
どんな救いの言葉も 聴き飽きたから 耳塞いでさ
I'm sick of hearing any comforting words, so I cover my ears
花びらたちと共に散って 楽になりたいよ ずっとかくれんぼっち
Scattering away together with the flower petals, I just want to find peace, always playing hide-and-seek all alone
いくらでも文句言えるよ その先に何もなくてさ
You can complain all you want, but there's nothing waiting at the end of it
こんな負の連鎖 飼い馴らして 他に趣味無いの?
Taming this negative chain like that, don't you have any other hobbies?
目に毒だって解ってるけど 見なきゃ気が済まないんだよ
I know it's poison to my eyes, but I can't help myself unless I look at it
だから止まない雨を見ている その汚い雨を
That's why I keep watching the ceaseless rain, that filthy rain
もういいかい？
Ready or not?
まだだよ
Not yet!
幕は上がり出した
The curtain has risen.
もういいかい？
Ready or not?
まだだよ
Not yet!
色付けていく ここから
Adding color from here on out
十年後の僕らは すれ違いばかりで
Ten years from now, we'll just keep passing each other by,
現象に思いを馳せては 戻れない
dwelling on phenomena, unable to return.
さぁ思い込んだ 傷だらけ 心に
Come on, into this scarred, self-absorbed heart,
澱みを あの頃と変わらない夕日も
stagnation... and the sunset that hasn't changed since back then,
何とも思わない
I don't feel a thing about them anymore.
自分を信じ 歩いてければ どこまでだって
If I could just believe in myself and keep walking,
登れるのに なぜか矛盾するその空白に
no matter how high I climb, why does this contradictory void
大切なもの見落としている
make me overlook what's truly precious?
見つけられないと 泣き叫ぶ 君へ
To you, crying out that you can't find it—
いっせーのーで声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
Raise your voice on "one, two, three" and hear it echo out!
自分の影の長さに気付く ももこんな時間だ
Realizing the length of my shadow, and that it's already this late.
一等星が顔を出した 孤独で手を伸ばした
The first-magnitude star poked its head out; feeling lonely, I reached out my hand.
次は僕に付いてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
Next time, follow me through any darkness!
もういいかい まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet!
幕は上がり出した
The curtain has risen.
もういいかい まだだよ
Ready or not? Not yet!
色付けていく ここから
Adding color from here on out.
宝箱は ホコリを 被ったままなくした
The treasure chest was lost, covered in dust.
鍵はずっと 君の ポケットの中にあった
The key was always inside your pocket.
ちらばっていた全てが 今ひとつに重なる
Everything that was scattered now overlaps into one.
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's take each other's hands and begin our story.
億千万のハートブレイク
Hundreds of millions of heartbreaks,
この青い星を抉る
gouging out this blue star.
吐き捨てた台詞はイノセンス
The words I spat out were innocence,
見つけて欲しくて泣いている
crying out because I wanted you to find me.
曇りのち雨
Cloudy, later rain.
かくれんぼする もういいかい？
Playing hide-and-seek. Are you ready?
まだだよ falling down まだだよ
Not yet, falling down, not yet.
もう探さないで…
Stop looking for me now...
ビルの隙間に覗く笑い
A smile peeking through the gaps of buildings,
low を誤魔化すためだけの high
a high just to disguise the low.
吸い殻と抜け殻捨てて fly
Throw away cigarette butts and empty shells and fly,
だけど僕らに帰る場所はない
but we have nowhere left to go home to.
いつからか君は 薬がないと笑えなくなってった
Before I knew it, you couldn't smile without pills.
何度追いかけても「大丈夫 僕はこんな運命だ」ってさ
No matter how much I chase: "I'm fine, this is my destiny."
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet.
痛みも苦しみも say good bye
Say goodbye to the pain and suffering.
半分噛み砕いて all night
Chewing it halfway down all night,
overdose してるみたい
like I'm overdosing.
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet.
わかってる君は精一杯 そんなに謝らなくても i know
I know you're trying your best, you don't have to apologize so much, I know.
手を繋いでいて i know you been feeling down
Hold my hand, I know you been feeling down.
been looking for you all around town
can you hear me calling can you hear me calling
億千万のストーリー
Hundreds of millions of stories,
この青い星を抉る
gouging out this blue star.
速度は増していくエンドレス
The speed increases endlessly,
動けずに肩をすぼめる i said i’m sorry
unable to move, huddling my shoulders. I said I'm sorry.
あの日渡した手紙は今日君の部屋の片隅の方
The letter I gave you that day is still in a corner of your room,
ただ落ちたままだったよ
just left fallen there.
Thank you! This is the best bday ever!
thank you for the best bday ever!
without you guys i never would have come this far
this idol rat will continue doing her best!
and this idol rat will continue doing her best!